妈妈!
mom!
我口渴
I'm thirsty.
你刚喝过水
I just gave you water.
我想喝果汁
I want juice.
很晚了
It's bedtime.
闭上眼睛睡觉
Close your eyesand go to sleep.
妈妈!
Mom!
你想干吗 clance?
What do you want,clance?
Oh 爸爸
Oh.Hi,dad.
睡觉去
Go to bed.
我能开着电视睡吗?
Can I turn the tv on?
电视只能白天看
Tv is only for the daytime.
我会把音量调小的,我想屋子里有光
I'll keep the volume down.I just like the light.
睡觉
Go to bed.
爸爸 如果...
Dad,what if...
如果他们又来抓我怎么办?
what if they cometo get me again?
没有人要抓你
Nobody is comingto get you.
好好睡觉,快点
Go to bed.Now.
妈妈!
Mom!
快点 clance,起床了
Come on,bud.It's time to get up--
哈 我想他已经起来了
I guess he's already up.
这可是头一次
That's a first.
我 呃 我去问他想吃什么
I-I will,uh,I'll seeif he needs breakfast.
嘿 clance 饿不饿?
Hey,clance,you hungry?
亲爱的 他不在楼下啊
Hon,he's not down here.
是吗?
You sure?
Clancy?
你在哪里?
Where are you?
亲爱的 你躲在哪儿了?
Sweetie,are you hiding?
- Clancy?,- 他去哪了?
- Clancy?,- Where is he?
Clancy?
等我找到你 有你好看
You're gonna bein big trouble when i find you.
亲爱的 不管你躲哪了 快点出来,这可不是好玩的
honey,come out right now,wherever you are.This is not funny.
Clancy?
-=豪斯医生=-,S03E02 "Cane & Able"
House,Season 03 Episode 02
啊 满身臭汗不见了?
Where's the sweat and the B.O.?
你曾经那么喜欢,让我们沉浸在你的汗臭中
You've taken such pride in bathing,us all in your musk.
在家冲凉了
Showered at home.
你还比平时早
And yet you're earlier than usual.
这算是心理治疗么?
Is this an intervention?
现在已经晚了 因为我已经戒了
It's a little late,,since I'm not using drugs anymore.
但是我对字母的瘾还没有戒
I am,however,still hooked on phonics.
如果你真的晨跑了 还在家冲凉的话,应该会比平时晚的
If you did your morning run and showered at home,,you'd be later than usual.
我冲凉的时候想你了
Thought of you in the shower.
你腿怎么样了?
How's your leg?
你好像喜欢用左腿
You seem to be favoring your left side.
我昨天把右边裤脚放长了,就这点区别
I was hanging down my right pant leg yesterday.Makes all the difference in the world.
- 你每天都爬楼梯,- 是不是要有法庭令你们才不烦我?
- You've taken the stairs every day.- Did I need a restraining order?
康复过程中不锻炼的话,肌肉会萎缩
You slack on your rehab,,the muscle will weaken.
你的腿又会疼
And your leg will hurt again.
看来k他命的治疗好像效果不佳
Looks like the ketamine treatment,might not stick.
也许是我们让他情绪低落,因为我们对他说谎了
Or maybe we've made him depressed,because we're lying to him.
说他的病例诊断错了
Telling him he got that case wrong.
我们没有伤害他,疼痛不是...
We didn't hurt him.The pain isn'T...
他变消极了 不做运动了
he gets depressed,he stops exercising.
他不运动的话 肌肉会萎缩
He stops exercising,the muscle atrophies.
肌肉一萎缩 疼痛就开始了
The muscle atrophies,the pain returns.
也许他停止运动是因为,他腿上的伤口真的很痛
Maybe he stopped exercising because,the giant hole in his leg actually hurts.
k他命的治疗没问题,现在他又要大吞止疼药了
The ketamine could work perfectly and he would,still be back on his cane popping vicon again.
不能告诉他
You can't tell him.
纯属运气 没有医学根据...
He got lucky.There was no medical...
他是对的
he was right.
告诉他他是对的,等于纵容他的毛病
We tell him he was right,and we're,feeding his addiction.
没有了止疼药 他只剩下一项嗜好
Without vicodin,he's only got,one to focus on.
猜病人的病症总好过服药过量
Well,he's not gonna O.D.On puzzles.
他自己的确没事
No,it's not gonna hurt him.
他可能会害死病人
But he could just as easily have,killed that patient.
我们有一个微小的机会,让House回归理性
We have a tiny window of time here where,house may be healthy enough to change.
从刚才他跛行的样子来看,这个机会正在逝去
And based on that limp,the window's closing fast.
小孩是试管婴儿 接种过疫苗
Kid is a product of an in vitro fertilization,pregnancy.Had all his vaccinations.
3岁时右手尺骨骨折,5岁出水痘
Fractured his right ulna at age three,,chicken pox at age fivE...
感情上有没有创伤?
did he ever get his feelings hurt?
这我也要知道
I'll need to know that too.
你回来以后还一分未得,我们至少想确认...
You are 0 for 1 since you came back.We just wanna make sure...
直肠出血还有外星人绑架的幻觉,很可能是性虐待症状
rectal bleeding plus alien abduction fantasies,,most likely sexual abuse.
插入导致流血 精神创伤导致幻想
Penetration causes the bleed,,trauma causes the fantasy.
急诊做过检查,未发现撕裂 精液和阴毛
E.R. Ran a rape kit,found no evidence,of tearing,semen,or pubic hairs.
应该和孩子谈谈
I think we should talk to the kid.
为什么?
Why?
难道他说的会是真话?
In case he's telling the truth?
你信这些的 对不对?
You're a believer,aren't you?
我只是没那么自大,毕竟有500亿个星系
I'm just not arrogant enough to think,that of the 50 billion galaxies,
每个星系有1000亿个恒星,宇宙间有几亿亿个行星
100 billion stars per galaxy and ten million,billion planets in the universe,
我们不会是唯一的生命
that we're the only ones with life.
不会
No.
不过我们是唯一一种,喜欢往后庭里插东西的生物
But I'm guessing we're the only ones who,like shoving things through our backdoors.
研究表明神经问题和出血紊乱有关联
There is new research indicating a link between,neurological problems and bleeding disorders.
是啊 特别是当病人有神经症状时
Perfect.Especially if there wereneurological problems.
外星人绑架幻觉还不是神经症状?
What part of hallucinating an alien,abduction isn't neurological?
不是幻觉
It wasn't a hallucination.
什么?
What?
- 你认为孩子真的遭绑架?,- 是做噩梦
- You think the kid...- is having nightmares.
噩梦不是病状,只表明小孩需要和妈妈睡
Nightmares aren'ta symptom of anything,other than wanting to sleep with mommy.
现在只剩下一个症状,流血的屁屁
Which just leaves uswith one symptom,,the bloody tuchus.
消化道疾病或出血性疾病可以解释
Which can easily be explained by a G.I.Problemor a bleeding disorder.
做血凝检查 PT/PTT(凝血酶原),还有出血时间
Check his coags with a pt,ptt,and bleeding time.
上下消化道都要做内镜
Prep him for endoscopiesfrom above and below.
要在你胳膊上轻轻扎一下
Gonna make a tiny nick in your forearm,okay?
然后看你要多长时间停止流血
Then I'm gonna time how longit,takes for you to stop bleeding.
有点点疼 你转过头去
This is gonnasting a little,,so you might want tolook the other way.
窗户是锁着的吗?
Are those windows locked?
这些窗户根本打不开,只是放进阳光
Those windowsdon't even open.They're just hereto let sunshine in.
好 因为他们知道我在这里
Good.'Cause they know I'm here.
clancy...
Clancy
别跟医生胡说
don't bother the doctorwith this stuff.
没事的 他们怎么知道你在哪?
No,it's okay.How do they know you're here?
他们在我脖子里装了芯片,可以追踪我
They put a chip in my neck,so they cankeep track of me.
我能感觉到
I can feel it back there.
Clancy 你知道那里什么也没有
Clancy,you knowthere is nothing back there.
有的
There is.
我看看 向前倾
Let me see.Lean forwards.
还装了别的东西,放在这两根肋骨中间
And they havethis other thing.And they put it...in between these two ribs.
一直在这边
Always on this side.
然后这东西在我身体里移动 很疼
And then they move itaround my insides.It hurts.
知道吗 Clancy?
You know what,clancy?
我可能找到芯片了
I think I might havefound the chip back there.
我可以取出来
And I think I might be able to get it out.
- 真的,- 嗯
- Really?,- Mmm-hmm.
好的 向前倾
Okay,lean forwards.
坐稳了不要动
Now hold very still,okay?
好了
Got it.
我7岁 不是3岁
I'm seven...not three.
你只不过捏了一下我的脖子
All you didwas pinch my neck.
不好意思
Sorry.
他的外星劫持的故事,详细的程度...
His alien abduction story,,the level of detail is...
我不知道他从哪里听来的
I don't knowwhere he gets it from.
他父母说他不看科幻片,不看漫画书
The parents sayhe doesn't watch sci-fi,,he doesn't read comic books.
好极了,你做了医学上的事情没有?
Great.You do any of thatmedical stuff we talked about?
上下消化道的内镜都没发现问题
Upper d lower endoscopieswere clean.
那么 就只是一种出血性疾病
So,it's a simplebleeding disorder.
不 血液测试全都正常,他的血液在六分钟内凝结
No. Blood testswere all normal.And he clotted insix minutes.
这么说 是简单的出血性疾病,你的测试做错了
So it's a simplebleeding disorder,and you screwed upthe test.
我没有做错
I didn't screw upthe test.
那么 这就是一个U.F.O.
So it's a U.F.O.
不明出血孔
Unidentified flowing orifice.
或者你检查出错,或者我的分析出错
Either youscrewed up the test or,i screwed upmy analysis of this case.
如果是你搞砸了 我不用负责
If you screwed up,I don't have,to cry myself to sleep.
是简单的出血性疾病,Foreman 重做测试
It's a simplebleeding disorder.Foreman,redo the test.
我怎么可能会搞砸一个,简单的出血时间试验?
How could I screw up a simplebleeding time test?
也许当时你被劫持了
Maybe you were abductedand lost time.
这个孩子有出血性疾病
Kid's got a bleeding disorder.
你确定?
You're sure?
流血25分钟 最后还是我止的血
I had to stopthe bleeding myself after 25 minutes.
所以 你是说Chase出错了
So you're sayingchase did screw up.
或者说Foreman出错了
Or foreman screwed up.
长针指示分钟  也许你搞混了
Big hand points to minutes.Maybe you got itmixed up.
噢 被鄙视了
Oh,snap.
Foreman在跟你打嘴仗呢,在文化上你可是大大的劣势 Chase,(playing dozens是黑人强项)
Foreman's playin'the dozens.You're at a huge cultural disadvantage here,chase.
花几分钟来想一个聪明的反击
Take a couple minutesto think of a witty retort.
我们出血时间试验结果相互矛盾
So we have contradictingbleeding time tests.
如果我们在试验室检测他的凝血因子,我们就可以确定谁是对的
If we run labsto check his clotting factors,,we can confirmwhich one's right.
测试 好主意
Yeah,testing.Nice idea.
比瞎猜哪个医生不合格好多了
Way better than trying to guess,which doctor's incompetent.
而且写在病历上也好看些
Looks betterin the paperwork too.
嘿 Foreman 你妈妈好肥
Hey,foreman,your mama's so fat,
她的呼机响起来的时候,人们都以为要倒车
when her beeper goes off,,people thinkshe's backing up.
Clancy在哪里?
Where's clancy?
他睡着了,他...
He's asleep.He'S...
house!
House!
Clancy不见了
Clancy's gone missing.
哦,不!
Oh,no!
你去人马座α星搜寻,Foreman去塔图音(星战地名)
You take alpha centauri,,foreman can look on tatooine,
Cameron在星系间设卡堵截
and cameron can set,upan intergalactic checkpoint.
祈祷一下他还没有进入超光速状态
Let's pray he hasn'tgone into hyperdrive.
那样就永远抓不到了
We'll never catch him.
Clancy?
我得到没有窗户的地方,那样我可以把芯片取出来 像你说的那样
I had to gowhere there are no windows,so I could getthe chip out like you said.
上帝啊
GoD.
- 我可以感觉的到 就是拿不出来,- Clancy 停下来!
- I can feel it,I just can't grab it.- Clancy,stop!
没有什么芯片
There is no chip.
我们会把你洗干净,然后把你送回房间
We're gonna clean you upand,we're gonna go back to your room.
你不能这样子做
You can't do thingslike this.
你的父母--
Your parents--
这东西可能不是地球上的
Said it might noteven be terrestrial.
真的?
Really?
不是 你个笨蛋 这是钛
No,you idiot,it's titanium.
比如因为手术植入的销子
Like from a surgical pin.
比如说这孩子四年前钉入断臂
Like the kind the kidhad inserted,into his broken armfour years ago.
不错的病史
Nice medical history.
那个销子在那之后六个月就被移除了
That pin was removedsix months after--
有一小块在移除过程中断掉了
so a little piece broke offduring removal.
钛被用来建造核潜艇,不会就这么断掉
Titanium is used to build nuclear subs.Pieces don't just break off.
告诉这家伙库尔斯克的事
Tell that to guyson the kursk.
那它到底怎么从他的手臂,转移到他的脖子后面
And how exactly did it getfrom,his arm to the back of his neck?
身体排斥任何的外物
Body attacksany foreign object.
炎症反应会使销子进入血管,碎片搭了个便车
Inflammatory reactioncould erode,it into a vein,fragment gets a free ride.
也许会到肺里面,而不是颈部
To his lungs,maybe.Not his neck.
对 外星人的芯片更说得通
Yeah,an alien chipmakes more sense.
奇怪的是你没有搞砸
The real mystery is that you,didn'tactually screw up.
你还好吧?
You okay?
没事 绊倒了
Fine.Tripped.
孩子在他的脖子后面挖了个洞,却没有因流血过多致死
Kid carved a hole in the back of his neck...and apparentlydidn't bleed to death.
这才是奇怪的
Now,that's weird.
他的血液自己凝固了?
He clotted on his own?
显然是的
Sure did.
所以开始没有出血性疾病,然后有了 现在又没有了
So first there wasno bleeding disorder,,then there was,now there is not again.
这不可能
Which is impossible.
或者说是Foreman搞砸了,三个测试中有两个和我的结论一致
Or foreman screwed up.Two out of three testsagree with my findings.
算我们运气 第四个检查就见分晓了
Well,lucky for us,,the fourth test will be the charm.
你们还要割他?
So you're just gonnakeep cutting him?
直到什么时候?
Until what?
这个测试不一样
This test is different.
我们抽取一些血样,看看是否有凝血因子不足或者缺失
We draw some blood and see if,any clotting factorsare low or missing.
但是为什么其他的测试没能够--
But whyhaven't the other tests--
我们得到三个不一致的结果,肯定其中有一个是错的
we've got three resultsthat haven't,been consistent.One of themmust be wrong.
或者其中两个
Or two of them.
有没有可能问题不是出在他的血液?
Is it possible the problemisn't his blood?
只是心理上的问题
It's just psychological.
我是说 他几乎杀死了自己
I mean,he almost killed himself.
他不是想要伤害自己
He wasn't tryingto hurt himself.
不...
No...
他只是在找一个外星跟踪装置
he was just looking for an alien tracking device.
我有时间再接一个病人
I have timefor one more.
你跑到这里加班 情有可原
Don't blame youfor spending extra time down here.
听说楼上的一个跛子行为艺术家回来了
Heard the artistformerly known,as gimp is back upstairs.
哦,Cuddy医生要了那个病例
Oh,dr.Cuddywants that one.
她很忙 我来接手了
She's busy.I'll take it.
哦 天哪 你是...
Oh,my god.You're...
怎么会...
how...
你好了
you're okay.
我们见过么?
Have we met?
我是你其中一个医生
I was one of your doctors.
上个星期你离开这里的时候,你还是植物人的状态
You were ina vegetative state,when you left here last week.
阿狄森氏病
Addison's disease.
我需要的就是一针可的松
All I needed was cortisol
就像按下开关一样我的大脑被启动了
and my brain turned onlike a switch.
这太让人惊讶了
This is amazing.
很惊讶你不知道
Surprised you didn't know.
我怎么会知道?
How would I know?
还没有完全回到过去的状态
Not quitemy old self yet.
婴儿学步 医生跟我说的
Baby steps,the doctors tell me.
就功能恢复来讲 你做的非常好,你去的是什么医院?
With rehab,you'll do great.What hospital did you go to?
- 我怎么会...- 我想要和我的妻子共享鱼水之欢
- How would I...- I wanna have sexwith my wife.
我想也许你可以...
And I was hoping that maybe...
你可以...
you could...
伟哥?,你来这里是为了要伟哥?
viagra?,You're here for viagra?
多开一些
A bucketfulwould be nice.
Cuddy医生
Dr.Cuddy.
嗨
Hi.
这完全不道德
It's completely unethical.
- 他对待病人不顾后果,- 他是正确的
- He was recklesswith a patient.- He was right.
但是他不知道这些,他需要至少谦卑一点点
But he didn't know that.He needs at leastsome glimmer of humility.
为什么他需要这么做?,因为其他人是这样的?
Why doeshe need that?,Because other peoplehave that?
他为什么需要像其他人一样?
Why does he need to belike other people?
他需要更多的考虑后果
He needs to beless reckless.
你成功了
Well,you did it.
他心不在焉,不求甚解 他很痛苦
He's dismissing symptoms,,looking for easy solutions.He's in pain.
- 多痛?,- 为什么问?
- How much pain?,- Why?
你知道这会影响到他 是么?
You know this isaffecting him,don't you?
告诉他他解决了上一个病例,不会对他有任何帮助
Telling him that hegot his last case,right won't do anything to help him.
- 这会减轻他的抑郁,- 这可能不会对他的腿有帮助
- It'll make himless depressed.- Which might nothelp his leg.
但是你说不准的
But you don't know.
就让我对他的丘脑做一个PET扫描,看看是不是感知到疼痛
Just let merun a pet scan on his parietal,thalamic area to see if it's sensing pain.
如果是的 K他命不会再起效果,而他就面临一个很大的消沉
If it is,the ketamineisn't working,anymore and he's headed fora huge crash.
如果不是 腿痛就是我的错误造成的,我会告诉他事实的
If it's not,the leg pain is my,fault and I willtell him the truth.
太紧么?
Too tight?
我父母认为我疯了
My parentsthink I'm crazy.
不 他们没有
No,they don'T.
他们只是为你担心 就只是这样
They're justworried about you,that's all.
我不是怪人
I'm not weird.
只是怪事老是发生在我身上
It's just that weird,thingskeep happening to me.
轻轻一下
Slight pinch.
如果你让我好转,外星人就不会来找我了吧
If you make me better,do you think,the alienswill leave me alone?
我想他们不会打扰你很长时间了
I don't thinkthey're gonna be,bothering you for much longer.
- 你又撒谎了?,- 没有
- You lying again?,- No.
我们找出病因,一切都会没事的
We figure this out,everything's gonna be okay.
你还清醒么?
You still with us?
肺水肿 高血压危象
Pulmonary edema,stage two hypertensive crisis.
- 发生了什么?,- 到外面等
- What is happening?,- Wait outside.
给他输氧,开始静脉点滴硝普钠
Get him oxygen.Start him on an iv drip of sodium nitroprusside.
让他们出去!
Get them outside!
他现在在重症监护病房,收缩压在170mmHg左右波动
He's in icu.Systolic is hoveringaround 170.
我下了医嘱 要缓慢降压,不能冒险 会造成器官供血不足
I left instructionsto lower it slowly so,we don't riskhypoperfusing his organs.
保持这么高的血压,会有中风 心梗和失明的危险
The trade-off being thatleaving his blood pressure,that high risks stroke,M.I.And blindness.
我广开言路的
I'm open to suggestions.
解决病例
Solve the case.
- 肾脏可以用来解释...- 肾脏没有问题
- Kidneys could explain...- kidneys are clean.
告诉我他是一个变异的人种
Tell me he's a mutant/human hybrid.
是出血性疾病,clancy的血友病检测阳性
It is a bleeding disorder.Clancy tested positive for von willebrand'S.
我没有搞砸
I didn't screw up.
他怎么可能三次里面两次,靠自身凝血止住出血
How could he clot on his owntwo,out of three times?
- 也许他作弊了,- 是啊
- Maybe he cheated.- right.
孩子总是在出血时间试验上作弊
Kids always cheat ontheir bleeding time tests.
她是在打比喻,她试着在模仿我
she was being metaphorical.She's tryingto sound like me.
我不知道你的意思是什么,但是我大概知道你葫芦里卖的是什么药
I have no ideawhat you meant,,but I could smellwhat the rock was cooking.
我是说他现在血液可以凝结,而且他处在高血压危象中
I meanthe's clotting right now,and he's inhypertensive crisis.
也许这两者有联系
Maybe the two e related.
可能另外两次他血液凝结的时候,是处于高血压中
What if he was hypertensive the,other two times that he clotted?
高血压危象可以激发凝血因子
Hypertensive crisiscan activate clotting factors.
如果von willebrands因子减少,理论上可以促进凝血
Someone low onvon willebrands,could theoretically clot.
而第一次Clancy凝血的时候,他都在激动的讲述他的外星劫持
And the first timeclancy clotted,he was all,worked uprecounting his alien abduction.
很可能会血压升高
He could have easilybeen hypertensive.
如果要我把脖子里的芯片取出,我也会变激动的
I know I get worked up when I cut,microchip trackingimplants out of my neck.
在我听起来像是作弊
Sounds like a cheat to me.
我们知道
Yeah,we get it.
多次高血压危象的七岁男孩,他的鉴别诊断是什么
Okay,what's the differentialfor seven-year-old,boys suffering multiplehypertensive crises?
我们认为问题是在你们儿子的心脏上
We think the problemis in your son's heart.
我们得做一个经食道超声检查
We need to do a procedurecalled,a transesophegeal echo.
好的 这可以治好他的心脏?
Okay,and that willfix his heart?
这可以告诉我们问题出在何处
That will tell uswhere the problem is.
希望如此
Hopefully.
然后我们可以治好他
Then we can fix him.
听着...
Listen...
这不是我的职责 但是...
this isn't reallypart of my job,but...
他担心你们认为他疯了
he's worried that you thinkhe's crazy.
难道没疯么?
Well,isn't he?
还有非常多其他的的解释
There are stillplenty of other,explanations for what's going on.
重要的是他知道你们相信他
It's important he knowsyou believe in him.
即使你们不相信
Even if you don'T.
没有问题,心脏不是问题所在
it's clean.His heartisn't the problem.
为什么我的办公室,就没有高清屏幕?
Why don't I have a hi defin my office?
我是部门头头
I'm a department head.
- 没有结构性缺陷,- 瓣膜完整
- There are nostructural defects.- Valves are intact.
象素点这么小 怎么辨认组织?
Tissue characterizationis impossible,when the pixelsare the size of legos.
看 这才像话!
See,this iswhat I'm talking about.
Foreman 帮我偷一个这
Foreman,you gottasteal this thing for me.
那我找找道上的朋友
Let me ring upone of the homies.
越清晰的图像,越证明没有肿块 没血块 没损伤
The clearer the image,the clearer it is,that there are no masses,no clots,no tears.
问题一定出在别处
The problem's got to be somewhere else.
我们需要更大的船
We're gonna needa bigger boat.
你错了 House
You're wrong,house.
他不会闹到IMAX影院才肯认错吧
Think he'll make usbreak into the,imax before he admits it?
- 那里,- 哪?
- There.- Where?
那里 左边 没有动
Right there.Left side.No movement.
别暂停
Well,don't freeze it.
某处没有动,全都不动怎么能看出某处没动
Something's not moving.How do you,seesomething not move if nothing's moving?
我要个激光笔
I need a laser pointer.
- 要激光笔干嘛?,- 为什么不可以?
- We don't havea laser pointer.- Well,why not?
没有激光笔太不像那么回事
Who's gonnatake us seriously,if we don't have a laser pointer?
这里
Right here.
几千个心肌细胞没有跟随其它的一起动
A few thousand myocytesnot,beating with the rest.
你发现心律不齐
So you foundan arrhythmia.
不是心律不齐 是根本没心率
That's not an arrhythmia.That's a no-rhythmia.
心肌细胞会收缩,这些根本没动
Myocytes contract.These aren't movingat all.
把它们切下来
Go get methose myocytes.
我要在办公室对它们训话
I want to talk to themin my office.
孩子怎么样?
How's the kid doing?
心脏几乎爆炸
Heart nearly exploded.
但还在跳动
Still beating,though.
至少大多数
Most of it anyway.
搞什么年龄限制 简直多此一举
Why do they botherputting age,restrictions on these things
总要点一下 "我已满18"
when all you have to do is click"yes,I am 18"?
17岁的也知道怎么做
Even a 17-year-oldcan figure that out.
你的腿怎么了?
What's going onwith the leg?
先告诉我你的胸怎么了
First tell me what's going onwith the boobs.
- 如果你感到疼痛,- 它们好似更挺了
- If you're feeling pain...- they're firmer.
因为有钢丝!
It's called an underwire.
我要对你的大脑做PET扫描
I wanna geta pet scan of your brain.
我想是荷尔蒙作用
I think it's hormones.
如果丘脑部没有异常
As long as there'sno increased,activity in the thalamus--
要我说简直可以加入乳品行业
looks to melike those puppies are,going intothe dairy business.
那么疼痛是好事
Then the pain can be good.
可能是肌肉再生
It could be muscleregenerating.
你锻炼 肌肉会酸痛,疼痛不代表K他命治疗失效
After you work out,you get sore.Pain doesn't meanthe ketamine failed.
也许我应该恭喜你,孩子爹是谁?
Guess I should be sayingmazel tov.Who gets to pass outthe cigars?
我没怀孕!
I'm not pregnant.
我要对你的大脑做PET扫描
I need to geta pet scan of your brain.
男孩女孩? 想好名字没有?
Boy or girl?,You got a name picked out?
- 我没怀孕,- 我的腿不疼
- I'm not pregnant.- My leg doesn't hurt.
- 你在逃避,- 不 我没有
- You're in denial.- No,I'm not!
好吧 算你赢
Oh,you got me.
如果我的腿在恶化
If I thought thatmy leg was deteriorating,
你以为我不会采取措施吗?
don't you think I'd want totake,steps to prevent that?
好吧
Okay.
要走了
Gotta go.
哈
Ha.
这是Clancy的DNA
Here's clancy's dna.
那是从心脏病灶活检取得的DNA
And here's the dnafrom that piece,of his heart we just biopsied.
不可能
That is impossible.
再做一次
Run it again.
已经重复过
We already did.
重复两遍
And once moreafter that.
心肌细胞的DNA和其它部位的不一致
The genesfrom clancy's myocytes,don't match the genesfrom the rest of his body.
异型DNA
Alien dna.
谁看科幻片的给点提示
Anybody watch any x-files that,inspired an explanation?
DNA有可能变异
there are waysdna can become mutated.
如果暴露在强紫外线下
Extreme uv radiation.
要有那么强的阳光,他的皮肤会变成健康的古铜色
That much sun,he'd be dying with,a healthy bronze glow.
亚硝酸或者溴化乙锭
Nitrous acid or ethidium bromide exposure.
他爸爸原先是性虐狂,现在成化学家了
First daddy was a rapist,now he's a chemist.
多种真菌能导致DNA变异
various species of fungus have,been proven mutagenic.
除非他狂吃芹菜,要么他住在印尼 或者两者皆有
Not unless the kid'sbeen eating barrels,of celery or livingin indonesia or both.
- 你的腿又疼了,- 这种问题有用么?
- Is your leg hurting?,- Is that question helping?
- 你站歪了,- 你坐着
- You're leaning.- You're sitting.
- 你在单脚站,- 我头疼
- You're evading.- My head's hurting.
请给我一个合适的
Please,someone give mea plausible,
不涉及外星生物的解释,关于孩子的异型DNA
terrestrial explanationfor,this kid's alien dna.
我们可以到他家寻找毒物,真菌或者辐射源
We could search his homefor toxins,,fungals,and radiation.
管他是什么导致的
Who cares what caused it?
小孩喉咙感染链球菌,我们会治好他
A kid comes in with a strep,,we don't conduct a search to see
而不是去研究哪个同学传染给他
which classmatehe got it from,we cure it.
知道有东西在他体内 那就切掉
We know he's got this inside him.Let's get a scalpeland cut it out.
在哪儿切?  也许不仅在心脏
Where do we cut?,Chances are it's notjust in his heart.
发现心脏的毛病是我们走运
we got luckywith the heart.
肌细胞会收缩 所以,能看出那些细胞没有动
Myocytes contract,we could see,that these weren't working.
别的地方有毛病怎么发现?
I don't know how the hellwe're,gonna find it anywhere else.
我们在带有不正常DNA的心肌上取样,然后标记它们怎么样?
What if we takethe heart cells,with the bad dnaand we tag them?
能打个比方吗?
Can you phrase thatin the form of a metaphor?
和我们寻找肿瘤是一个办法
It's the same waywe search for cancer.
异常DNA会在细胞表面,产生独特的蛋白质
The bad dna creates a unique protein,on the surface of the affected cells.
我们再合成一种,只能识别那种蛋白质的抗体
We create an antibodythat recognizes,only that protein.
然后向他体内注入大量这样的抗体,那些相应的细胞就会...
We flush it throughout his system,and the similar cells light up like...
像灯泡一样亮起来
lightbulbs.
好 就这么干了
Okay.Let's do that.
你们得告诉他
You have to tell him.
- 他说他一点也不疼,- 他在骗你们
- He said he wasn'tin any pain.- He's lying.
那是当然
Of course he's lying.
得订一个新计划
We need another plan.
别那么说
Don't talk about itthat way.
别怎么说?
What way?
计划 听起来就像,我们在对他耍什么阴谋诡计
Plan.Sounds likewe're conspiring against him.
- 我要去告诉他,- 你不能说
- I'm gonna tell him.- No,you're not.
那就赶紧订一个巧妙的计划
Then come upwith a cunning plan and fast.
她一定也不像她想象的那样讨人喜欢
She's not nearly as delightfulas,she thinks she is.
这机器是干嘛的?
What's this machine do?
它制造出好多噪音
It makes a lot of noise.
同时帮我们看看你到底出啥问题了
And it's gonna help usfigure out,what's wrong with you.
你认为 House 走错了一步?
You think househas lost a step?
他没事
He's fine.
在那 股骨骨髓中有一团受侵袭的细胞
There,a clump of affected cellsin,the bone marrow of the femur.
解释了为什么有断断续续的出血紊乱
Explains the intermittentbleeding disorder.
如果House不比我们强,我不必屈服于他的折磨
'Cause I don't need tosubject myself,to house's tortureif there's no upside.
我说了 他没问题
I'm telling you,he's fine.
我们还遗漏了其他受侵袭的心肌细胞
We missed some affected cells in his heart.
这解释了他持续的高血压问题
Explains the continuinghypertensive issues.
你说他的上一个病例打击了House,怎么你现在突然...
You said the last casereally threw him.And now suddenly...
我说错了
I was wrong.
所以你改变主意了
So you changedyour mind.
为什么?
Why?
他在这个病例上的,所有天才想法都是你的
His brilliant ideason this case,have all been yours.
他为什么需要带眼镜?
There's the reason for him needing glasS.
很明显这是一种病症,说明他的病很早就...
Apparently it's a symptom.Means the condition predates--
没原因的话你是不会改变主意的
you don't change your mindwithout a reason.
你知道什么了?
What do you know?
House...
在上个病例里没有错
didn't blow the last case.
Cuddy用House的建议治好了那人
Cuddy cured the guyusing house's idea.
但Cuddy和 Wilson想教他学会谦虚
Cuddy and wilsonare trying to,teach him some humility.
扫描完了 三个病灶,但是没有一个在大脑中
Scan is complete.Three hot spots,but nothing in his brain.
House 原来的理论是对的
House's original theorywas right.
不是神经方面的问题
It is not neurological.
以后他还能走路吗?
is he gonna be able to walk?
恢复后他的腿应该还是有功能的
his leg should be functional after some rehab.
有功能? 什么意思?
Functional?,What does that mean?
他能走 但是不能跑?,他会瘸吗?
He's be able to walkbut not run?,He'll have a limp?
如果一切顺利的话 他能走也能跑
If everything goes well,he'll walk,he'll run.
甚至会比现在更强壮
He'll probably beeven stronger than he is now.
当他被麻醉后 我们打开他的腿
Whwhen we close him up,we'll move,over to his other leg.
把一根导管从股动脉插进去直到心脏
Snake a catheter up through the femoral,artery and into his heart.
当异常细胞被移走后,正常组织就可以行使功能
Once the affected areas are removed,,his normal tissue will set back in and do its job.
他也不该再会有血压方面的问题了
He should have no more problemswith,his blood pressure.
当我们确定那些区域已经清除干净后,就会进行最后的程序
After confirmingthose areas are clear,,we'll startthe final procedure.
我将向瞳孔中插入一根针,把视网膜上的那些异常细胞清除掉
I'm gonna insert a needlethrough the pupil,and get rid of theabnormal cells in the retina.
把右眼闭上
Close your right eye.
能看到我的脸吗?
Can you see my face?
能 很清楚
Yeah.It's clear.
你可以把你的眼镜扔掉了,一切搞掂
You can throw awayyour glasses.We got it all.
睡会儿吧
Get some sleep.
明天你就回家了
You're going home tomorrow.
谢谢你
Thank you.
想出去跑跑吗?
You wannago for a run?
你想干啥?
What do you want?
我想你没事跑跑
I want you to run.
你什么时候变成一个促进者了?
When did youbecome an enabler?
我想敦促你多运动运动
I'm enabling youto exercise.
Vicodin(止痛药)阻止了疼痛,你挺过了你的恢复期
Vicodin blocks the pain,,you get through your rehab.
肌肉力量增强 疼痛减少
Muscle strength increases,and pain decreases.
我可不想靠止痛片来过日子
I'd rather not becomedependent on,pain pills to get through my day.
你和其他病人真是太像了
You're just likeany other patient.
装作不知道不会使你快乐
Running away from knowledgethat,won't make you happy.
我就像个撇大条的小猪一样快乐
I'm as happyas a pig in poop.
你害怕K他命的治疗效果会逐渐消失
You're scared the ketaminetreatment's,wearing off.
那只是一个...
That it was just A...
通向美好生活的一个痛苦窗口
torturous windowto the good life.
是哪一部分大条难道你不知道吗?
What part of poopdidn't you understand?
为什么你如此肯定那不是肌肉酸痛?
How can you be so sureit isn't,just a sore muscle?
因为这是我的腿
It's my leg.
我们认识彼此很久了
We've known each othera long time.
你并不总是对的 House
You're not always right,house.
你近来已有证明
You've proven that lately.
- 他怎么了?,- 他癫痫发作了
- What's happening to him?,- He's seizing.
- 给我氯硝安定,- 我以为你们都治好了!
- I need clonazepam.- I thought you got it all!
好 继续朝我吼,那样孩子就能治好了
Yeah,yell at me.That'll fix the kid.
显然我们遗漏了某些外来的组织,还有一些在他的体内
bviously we missedsome foreign tissue.There's somethingstill in him.
幻觉的发作意味着颞前叶出了问题
The hallucinationsand seizures,indicate problemsin the temporal lobe.
对不起 House 这是个神经上的问题
Sorry,house,it is neurological.
看起来你又错了一次
Looks likeyou were wrong,again.
我们什么也没漏掉
We didn't miss anythinG.
大脑的扫描一点问题也没有
The brain scanwas completely clean.
我们的标记物一定没有穿透血脑屏障
Our tag must not have penetratedthe,blood brain barrier.
这次不要走静脉了,直接进大脑
Don't use an iv this time,,get it right into the brain.
没有细胞亮起来
no cells are lighting up.
他的大脑没问题
His brain is clean.
不是神经问题
It is not neurological.
他的症状是神经性质的
His symptomsare neurological.
肯定是由神经引起的
His conditionhas to be neurological.
扫描了两次都没问题
His scan was clean twice.
不在大脑里
It's not there.
会不会它就在那里 而只是扫描不出来呢?
What if it is there,,but didn't show up on the scan?
会不会标记物在大脑里没用了呢?
What if the tagjust doesn't work,in his brain?
大脑细胞的结构是不同的,他们表达不同的蛋白质
Brain cellsare structurally different.They express a different protein.
那我们怎样才能发现它?
So how do we find it?
我们去哪?
Where are we going?
我去思考
I am going to think.
把那孩子送回家
Send the kid home.
你是什么意思?
What do you mean?
确保他的血压正常 把他送回家
Make sure his blood pressureis,stabilized and send him home.
就像什么事都没发生一样?
Like nothing ever happened?
我们治好了他的出血紊乱
We curedhis bleeding disorder
清除了所有我们能发现的被损坏细胞
and removed all the damagedcells we could find.
我们并不知道我们治好了什么,这才一天
We don't knowthat we fixed anything.It's only been a day.
也许这些症状就会像,出血紊乱一样间歇发作
Maybe these symptoms come and go,like the blood disorder.
更有可能他其余的症状仅仅只是
It's more probablethat his remaining symptoms are
一个恶梦
just a nightmare.
可他产生了惊厥
He had a convulsion.
也许是癫痫 也许是心理疾病
Maybe epilepsy,maybe psychological.
也许什么都不是
Maybe nothing.
如果孩子又病了 会给我们,新的线索 我们再次调查
If the kid gets sick again,that'll give us,another clue and we'llstart searching again.
如果没有 那就没事了
If he doesn't,it doesn't matter.
送他回家吧
Send him home.
House!
你就这么放弃这个孩子了
You're just giving upon this kid?
你得知道什么时候该停手
You gotta knowwhen to stop.
可你不会停手
You don't stop.
你从不会停手,你会一直坚持下去直到做出一些
You never stop,you just keep on,going until you come up
常常是正确的疯狂事情
with something so insane that,it's usually right.
除了上个病例
Except on my last case.
别装可怜
Don't be pathetic.
忘了上个病例吧
Just forgetthe last case.
这孩子明显有些不对头
This kid obviouslyhas something wrong with him.
什么时候你对我的病人,有如此强硬的主张了?
When did you developsuch strong,opinions about my patients?
上星期你还确信我的病人没病
Last week you were convinced that,my patient wasn't sick.
现在你又确信这个有病
Now you're convincedthis one is.
因为这是一个小男孩
This oneis a young boy.
他爸妈都绝望了
His parents are desperate.
只需回到你的团队,多花一点时间...
Just get togetherwith your team,,spend a few extra hours...
好吧 我想我们可以切除他的左腿
well,I guess we couldamputate his left leg.
在那里发现最多,还要把受侵袭的眼球摘掉
It's wherewe found most of it.Maybe we,should just removehis affected eye completely.
如果你相信那养对他好...
If you have reason to believethat,that might help...
我不会去切他的身体
I'm not gonna startlopping off body parts.
但是很有意思 你给我开了绿灯
But it's interesting that yougive,me the green light.
我只是想你有所作为
I just want youto do something.
这一个星期来你的支持已经过头了
You've been overly supportivethis,entire week.
要么是受到荷尔蒙,要么是负罪感的驱使
Well,either you're hormonal or you're,guilt-ridden.
当然对于怀孕来说,受到荷尔蒙影响还早了些
And it's too earlyin the pregnancy,for this to be hormonal.
- 我没有怀孕,- 那你做错什么了?
- I'm not pregnant.- Then what did you do wrong?
他确实有阿狄森氏病
He had addison'S.
你的上个病人 你是对的
Your last patient.You were right.
我给他打了一针可的松,然后他就像 Rip Van Winkle 一样醒来,(美国短篇小说，其主人公一觉睡了20年)
I gave him one shot of cortisoland,he work up like rip van winkle.
噢 你妈妈碰到麻烦了
Oh,your mommy'sin such trouble.
她是个骗子
She's such a liar.
这就是你为啥没有老爸,为啥她不得不...
That's why youdon't have a daddy.That's why she had to...
一个人怎么可能...
how does one person...
带着两套不同的 DNA?
end up withtwo different sets of dna?
- 我们已经谈过了,- 我们的假设不对
- We've been through this.- Our assumptions are faulty.
我们已经确认有两套 DNA,序列测了不止一次
We've confirmedtwo different sets of dna.We re-ran the sequence.
我没说实验室搞错了,我是说我们的假设错了
I didn't say the lab workwas faulty,,I said our assumptionswere faulty.
我们假设他是一个人
We assumedhe's a person.
当然了 外星人不仅仅拜访了他,还把他给换了
Of course.The aliensdidn't just visit him,,they replaced him.
你真笨
You're being silly.
如果他不是一个人 而是两个人?
What if he's not a person?,What if he's two persons?
- 我不懂你的比喻,- 没有比喻
- I'm not gettingthe metaphor.- No metaphor.
Chase说他妈妈曾接受过人工授精 对吗?
Chase said the mom used in vitro,fertilization,right?
是的 他们无法受孕
Yeah,they had troubleconceiving.
孩子一直没问题,直到他被植入了某些东西
Kid was right all along.He was implanted with something.
回到他小时候 我是说,很小的时候 比如只有12个细胞时
Back when he was young.I mean,really young.Like 12 cells young.
体外培养增加了双胞胎的可能性
In vitro increasesthe likelihood of twinning.
可是他没有孪生兄弟
But he doesn't havea twin.
别绕远了...
Not walking around...
但人工授精费用是2万5千美金
but in vitro fertilization costs,around 25 grand a pop.
所以要移植2到6个胚胎,以使物有所值
So doctors implant two to six embryos,to make sure you get your money's worth.
问题是 并不总有足够的卧室,给这些小宝贝们住
The problem is,there's not always,enough bedrooms for all the kiddies.
所以两兄弟就不得不分享一个空间,却没有上下铺
Two brothers get stuck sharing,,but there's no bunk beds.
所以他们就抱在一起取暖,而且再也不会分开
So they cuddle up to keep warm,and they never untangle.
他是合二为一
He's two people in one.
这就叫嵌合体,(Chimera 希腊神话中的合体怪物)
It's called chimerism.
不幸的是 他兄弟...
Unfortunately,his brother'S...
像是一个坏的替身
like a bad doubles partner.
那家伙只是占据空间 拦在路上
The guy just takes up space,gets in the way.
Clancy的身体认为能将他轻松干掉
Clancy's body thinks he's gonnaput,away the easy winners,
但他兄弟一直发挥出色
his brother just keepsswatting,the balls into the net.
我们得把他从球场上拽下来了
We gotta get himoff the court.
你能找出他大脑中的坏细胞?,能还是不能?
So does that meanthat you can find,the bad cellsin his brain or not?
好吧 不用比喻形式也可以
Sure,abandon the metaphor.Fine.
Clancy 和他兄弟想得不一样,因为他也在思考
Clancy thinks differentlythan his brother...because he thinks.
如果我们诱导一个外星人诱拐行动...
If we inducean alien abduction...
等等 你到底在说什么?
wait,what the hellare you talking about?
你儿子的脑中一直有外来DNA
The foreign dnahas got to be in the,portionof your son's brain
所以他相信自己被诱拐了
that makes him believe that he's being abducted.
用电极刺激这些神经元,就能哄骗你儿子的大脑产生幻觉
If we stimulate those neuronswith an electric,probe,we can trick your son's braininto hallucinating.
你儿子的神经元就会亮起来,而他兄弟的细胞会继续保持黑暗
Your son's neurons will light up,,and his brother's cellswill remain dark.
那就是我们要切除的部分
Those are the oneswe cut out.
你是在说一个脑外科手术
You're talking aboutbrain surgery.
我说的是一个很酷的脑外科手术
I'm talking aboutreally cool brain surgery.
你的一个儿子会死
One of your sons will die.
但是个子高的那个,再也不会有人烦他
But the taller one won't beso annoying anymore.
这么说我有一个孪生兄弟?
So I have a twin?
不一定
Not really.
卡片上有什么?
What's on the card?
电灯泡
Light bulb.
让我们从10开始
Start us out at ten.
我没有动
I'm not doing that.
是我做的 孩子 对不起
It was all me,kid.Sorry.
你在活动区域
You're in motor function.
试着往后退2厘米
Try two centimeters back.
他住在我身体里
He lives inside me.
差不多
Sort of.
好痒 别挠我的脚了
That tickles.Stop tickling my feet.
你到了感知区域 再近点
You're in sensory.Getting closer.
- 这张上你看到了什么?,- 月亮和星星
- What do you seeon this one?,- Moon and stars.
那么...
So...
我是不是很奇怪?
I am kind of weird?
我们都很奇怪
We're all kind of weird.
不!
No!
- Clancy?,- 有状况
- Clancy?,- We got something.
- 你看到什么了?,- 光
- What do you see?,- The light.
他们来了 我想
Here they come.I think.
脑电波显示轻度幻觉
Brain waves indicate mild hallucination.
- 神经元亮起来了,- 那些暗点呢?
- Neurons are lighting up.- Any dark spots?
- 区域太模糊了,- 幻觉还不够强烈
- area's too fuzzy.- Hallucinationisn't strong enough.
提高刺激强度
Turn up the juice.
他的血压已经160/110了,再高的话...
His blood pressure's alreadyat 160 over 110.Any higher and...
变傻瓜总比没命好
riding the short bus is betterthan not breathing.
加到100
Take us to 100.
区域还是太模糊了,无法区别
Area's still too fuzzy to make,any kind of distinction.
再加高
Crank it up higher.
你已经超过预设的最大值了
You've already exceededthe pre-set maximum.
再加下去大脑就要被毁了
Next step's brain damage.
他们要抓走你,他们正穿过围墙
They're gonna get you.They're comingthrough the walls.
他们要抓走你 折磨你
They're gonna take you,torture you.
你再也看不到你爸妈了
You'll never see your parents again.
Clancy 能听到我说话吗?
Clancy,can you hear me?
Clancy?
你抓到他们了
You got them.
一点没错
Yep.
把他们全抓住了
We got 'em all.
收尾吧
Close him up.
一切再次恢复正常
Everything's gonnabe normal again.
你相信Cuddy会耍我吗?
You believe what cuddytried to pull?
又怎么了?
What now?
她骗了我
She lied to me.
她利用我的诊断治好了我的病人,然后她撒了谎
She cured my patientwith my diagnos,,then she lied about it.
听起来可不像她
That doesn'tsound like her.
没错
You're right.
但是像你
Does soundlike you,though.
Cuddy到底跟你说了什么?
What exactlydid cuddy tell you?
和你现在的身体语言所告诉我的一样
Nothing thatyour body language,isn't telling me right now.
计划是怎样的?
So what was the plan?
由于无法治好一个病人,而变得如此谦逊...
I'd feel so humbled by missing a case...
重新评估我的整个生活,领悟真和善 变成 Cameron?
that I'd re-evaluatemy entire life,question,the natureof truth and goodness,and become cameron?
差不多是那样的
Something like that.
如果我们告诉你真相
More that if we told you the truth,
你解决了一个病例,却不基于任何医学证据
that you'd solved a casebased on,absolutely no medical proof,
你会认为自己是上帝的
you'd think you were god.
我担心你的翅膀会融化,(希腊神话英雄Icarus)
And I was worriedyour wings would melt.
上帝不会瘸的
God doesn't limp.